Guide to the Benoit Mandelbrot Papers M1857
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 23. Artwork and Artifacts
  - Subseries 1. Artists
    - Nat Friedman, prints (visual work); dedicated to Mandelbrot, 1994 (Map-folder 521)
    - Leon Gaignebet, prints (visual work), circa 1993 (Flat-box 457, Folders 1-8)
    - Sidney Harris and others, cartoon art (Box 505, Folder 6)
    - Roger Honorat, letter and fractal art, 1992-1994 (Box 505, Folder 8)
    - Kiyoshi Iwata, Micro Map, 1993 (Map-folder 524)
    - Kiyoshi Iwata, Micro Map, 1994 (Flat-box 476, Folder 2)
    - Kiyoshi Iwata, prints on plastic film (prints are damaged and peeling; prints have been in encapsulated to prevent further damage.) (Map-folder 538)
    - Irwin Jungreis, fractal art (Flat-box 513, Folder 6)
    - Paul Kolker; Benny; portrait of Mandelbrot (fracolor, inkjet print on canvas) 2006 (Flat-box 455)
    - Gyorgy Kepes, sample palette of faceted glass; used for installation of stained glass window, 1981 (Flat-box 440)
    - Francoise Labbe and Serge Salat, Infinite Memories (booklet), 1992; inscribed to Mandelbrot (Half-box 532, Folder 6)
    - Early geometric drawings by Mandelbrot, circa 1942-1944 (Flat-box 472, Folders 1-5)
    - Bob Nash, ink drawings, circa 1962-1972 (Flat-box 448, Folders 1-5)
    - Bob Nash, ink drawing, 1968 (Flat-box 449, Folder 1)
    - Therese Oulton (exhibit catalog), 2003 (Half-box 532, Folder 8)
    - Peter Raedschelders, print on paper (visual work) (Flat-box 491, Folder 4)
    - Peter Raedschelders, prints (visual work), 2007 (Flat-box 475, Folder 4)
    - Vytas Sakalas, "Fractal" (lithograph) (Flat-box 516, Folder 2)
    - Vytas Sakalas, prints on paper (visual work) (Flat-box 491, Folder 5)
    - Charles Seliger, Chaos to Complexity (exhibit catalog), 2003 (Half-box 532, Folder 3)
    - Charles Seliger, exhibition notice: New Paintings, 2006 (Flat-box 348, Folder 2)
    - Stephen Shore, terrain photograph, 1988 (Flat-box 491, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2. Miscellaneous Artwork and Artifacts
    This subseries contains work by unidentified artists as well as natural and manufactured artifacts, such as minerals. The material is organized roughly by subject matter or alphabetically when possible.
    - 2-D discrete Fourier transform (Box 534)
    - Aluminum contour form (Box 446)
    - Artifacts; includes coral, minerals, sculpture (Box 445)
    - Cell Imaging Scientists, fractal image (Flat-box 491, Folder 7)
    - Computer graphics and applications cover-transparencies, Jan 1989 (Flat-box 348, Folder 4)
    - Contour landscape, drawing (Flat-box 513, Folder 2)
    - Diffusion Limited Aggregation (DLA), artwork (Flat-box 516, Folders 3-4)
    - Diffusion Limited Aggregation (DLA) images (negatives) (Box 505, Folder 3)
    - Diffusion Limited Aggregation (DLA), pieces 1-6; computer rendering mounted on foam core; pieces form one large mural. (Flat-box 407, Folders 1-6)
    - Diffusion Limited Aggregation (DLA), pieces 7-12; computer rendering mounted on foam core; pieces form one large mural. (Flat-box 410, Folders 1-6)
    - Diffusion Limited Aggregation (DLA), pieces 13-18; computer rendering mounted on foam core; pieces form one large mural. (Flat-box 411, Folders 1-6)
    - Diffusion Limited Aggregation (DLA), pieces 19-25; computer rendering mounted on foam core; pieces form one large mural. (Flat-box 412, Folders 1-7)
    - Diorama cartography (plexiglass) (Othercontainertype 447)
    - Fractal art (Flat-box 514, Folder 4)
    - Fractal art (Flat-box 516, Folder 7)
    - Fractal art (color prints) (Flat-box 513, Folder 4)
    - Fractal art, prints (visual work) on foam core (Flat-box 474, Folders 1-3)
    - Fractal art, print (visual work), 1993 (Flat-box 475, Folder 3)
    - Fractal art, print (visual work) (Flat-box 475, Folder 5)
    - Fractal art, Flare (Flat-box 474, Folder 4)
    - Fractal Art: Beauty and Mathematics (exhibit catalog), 2006 (Half-box 532, Folder 7)
    - Fractal art/fractal-related computer art (Flat-box 494, Folders 1-7)
    - Fractal images/art (Box 500, Folder 4)
    - Fractal images and cover art for books (transparencies) (Box 505, Folder 4)
    - Fractal images (negatives) 1988 (Box 505, Folder 2)
    - Fractal images for publications (Box 505, Folder 5)
    - Fractal images; black and white polaroid series (contour landscape visualizations, other images) (Half-box 506, Folders 1-2)
    - Fractal Forms (booklet), 1991 (Half-box 532, Folder 1)
    - Fractal landscapes (computer art) (Flat-box 491, Folder 8)
    - Fractal landscapes (computer art) (Flat-box 492, Folder 3)
    - Fractal landscapes (computer art) (Flat-box 516, Folder 8)
    - Fractal landscapes - contact sheets (computer art) (Flat-box 516, Folder 9)
    - Fractal landscape; print on transparency (Map-folder 523)
    - Fractal map (Flat-box 514, Folder 5)
    - Fractal maps (Map-folder 519)
    - Fractal Planet Rise, computer art (print in plexiglass frame with IBM logo) (Flat-box 450)
    - Fractal Planet Rise, computer art (color separations) (Flat-box 454, Folders 1-2)
    - Fractal-related art (Flat-box 491, Folders 9-10)
    - Fractal-related art (Flat-box 516, Folders 5-6)
    - Fractal-related art (Flat-box 348, Folders 6-7)
    - Fractal-related art; possibly satellite image of topography (Map-folder 522)
    - Fractal visualizations; includes Mandelbrot set, others (color prints) (Flat-box 516, Folder 11)
    - Fractal inspired sculpture (Box 536)
    - Fractals 2000 in Biology and Medicine; print (visual work) for Mandelbrot (Map-folder 528)
    - Haebel, fractal prints (visual work), booklet (Box 500, Folder 7)
    - The Internet (poster); paths from Bell Labs, 1999 (Map-folder 527)
    - Karskaya (exhibit catalogs) (Box 503, Folder 2)
    - Lichtenberg figures (Box 439)
    - Magazine clipping; volcano image (Flat-box 513, Folder 5)
    - Mandelbrot Set, color image (Flat-box 475, Folder 6)
    - Manganese and iron oxide dendrites (Flat-box 442)
    - Matematikak eta Artea (exhibit catalog) (Half-box 532, Folder 5)
    - Painting on canvas, (fractal-inspired abstraction) 1986 (Flat-box 452)
    - Painting on glass (Flat-box 537)
    - Portraits of Benoit Mandelbrot, ink on paper (Flat-box 491, Folder 12)
    - Portrait of Benoit Mandelbrot (visual work) (Flat-box 494, Folders 9)
    - Portrait of young Benoit Mandelbrot, painting on board canvas (Flat-box 494, Folders 10)
    - Knit portrait of Benoit Mandelbrot (Flat-box 516, Folder 1)
    - Fan art; framed portrait of Mandelbrot with plastic wire installation (Box 535)
    - Print (visual work) (Flat-box 476, Folder 6)
    - Sandstone (Flat-box 441)
    - Satellite image/topographical map (Flat-box 494, Folders 8)
    - Universal Sheets, artwork, postcard, and flyer (Flat-box 514, Folder 1)
    - Visualizations (color), undated (Flat-box 348, Folder 9)
    - Visualizations (landscapes, Mandelbrot set, graphs, other images) (Flat-box 475, Folders 1-2)
- Series 24. Photographic Material
  This series contains photographic prints, negatives, slides, and photo albums. Subject matter includes formal portraits of Mandelbrot as well as informal photographs from conferences and other events. Also included are photographs of fractals used for research, teaching, presentations, and publications.
  - Photograph album - 25 Years of Service with the IBM Corporation (Flat-box 236, Item 1)
  - Photograph album - Technion-Israel Institute of Technology - Dr. Benoit B. Mandelbrot, Laureate of the 1989 Harvey Prize in Science and Technology - Technion City - Haifa, Israel, 1989 Jun 21 (Flat-box 236, Item 2)
  - Slides - DLA (Box 203, Folders 1-2)
  - Slides - Mountains and Islands (Voss) (Box 203, Folders 3-5)
  - Slides - Non-Conformal Mapping (Box 203, Folders 6-7)
  - Slides - Musgrave & Miscellaneous (Box 203, Folders 8-9)
  - Slides - Text (Box 204, Folders 1-3)
  - Slides - M-Sets and Julia Sets (Box 204, Folders 4-5)
  - Slides - Miscellaneous (Box 204, Folders 6-8)
  - Slides - Bremen (Box 204, Folders 9-10)
  - Slides - Quarternions (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - Slides - FGN (B+W) I [Fractal Geometry of Nature] (Box 205, Folders 2-4)
  - Slides - FGN (B+W) II [Fractal Geometry of Nature] (Box 205, Folders 5-6)
  - Slides - Siggraph '84 Computer - Aided Design Arts Show Slide Set (Box 205, Folder 7)
  - Slides - Voss; Words Misc. - Barnes Voss; Kischko (Box 205, Folder 8)
  - Slides - Siggraph '84 Technical Slide Set (Box 205, Folder 9)
  - Slides - 21; 25; Me fractalized (Box 205, Folder 10)
  - Slides - Art; DLA's Nature; Fract. Planet (Box 205, Folder 11)
  - Slides - Quaternion (sheets 1-9) (Box 206, Folder 1)
  - Slides - English text - Old Price (1963); Chris Walter; DLA Hamburg (3 Sheets) (Box 206, Folder 2)
  - Slides - Dragon bad photos; [New York Notes presentation slides]; [?] Voss 1982; [White]; [New White] (Box 206, Folder 3)
  - Slides - Ken Mountains; Mountains; Ken Mtns; Ken; Old Ken (Box 206, Folder 4)
  - Slides - DLA; DLAs Hamburg; Art (Box 206, Folder 5)
  - Slides - English text; French titles; Frank dubious; Cauliflower; Nobel (Box 206, Folder 6)
  - Slides - DLA; B. Mandelbrot 28.028; Mandelbrot Book Jackets; Shaun slides (Box 206, Folder 7)
  - Slides - Misc. Dragons Matrix; Clouds for Shaun (Box 206, Folder 8)
  - Slides - Duplicate March '82; Real Art; 2.5; Smithsonian (Box 206, Folder 9)
  - Slides - Hubbard (Box 207, Folder 1)
  - Slides - Hubbard? (Box 207, Folder 2)
  - Slides - Cloud; Inca; Cloud Moon (Box 207, Folder 3)
  - Slides - Dragon; Dr. Tail; No Planet. No Dragon Extras of Color Signature (Misc.) (Box 207, Folder 4)
  - Slides - Garish M. Sets (Apollo?); B.B.M.; B. Photos by Sheridan & others (Box 207, Folder 5)
  - Slides - Glasgow 5/3/91; Klein; M-set; Giacometti; Escultura Iberica, Museo Arqueologico Nacional Madrid (Box 207, Folder 6)
  - Slides - Mandelbrot portraits (Box 207, Folder 7)
  - Slides - [Slides from Carousel] (Box 207, Folder 8)
  - Slides - Siggraph '88 Art Slide Set, edited by; Lucy Petrovich, Lisa Fremont. Ref. Computer Graphics, vol. 22, no. 5 (Box 207, Folder 9)
  - Slides - 3-D Julia set-slides + Correspondence with Stewart Dickson, 1993-09-13 (Box 207, Folder 10)
  - Slides - Slides of Sculpture by and correspondence from Rick Clement, 1992 (Box 207, Folder 11)
  - Slides - Slides, Photographs and correspondence from Dr. Michael Michelitsch, Feb. 1989 (Box 207, Folder 12)
  - Slides - [Unlabeled Set #'s 1-4] (Box 208, Folder 1)
  - Slides - [Unlabeled Set #'s 5-10] (Box 208, Folder 2)
  - Slides - [Unlabeled Set #'s 11-16] (Box 208, Folder 3)
  - Slides - [Unlabeled Set #'s 17-21] (Box 208, Folder 4)
  - Slides - [Unlabeled Set #'s 22-25] (Box 208, Folder 5)
  - Slides - [Unlabeled Set #'s 26-29] (Box 208, Folder 6)
  - Slides - [Unlabeled Set #'s 30-37] (Box 208, Folder 7)
  - Slides - [Unlabeled Set #'s 38-44] (Box 208, Folder 8)
  - Slides - [Unlabeled Set #'s 45-48] (Box 209, Folder 1)
  - Slides - [images 1990 Jeffrey Ventrella]; Special [Bremer (Prime)]; Notre-Dame de Paris (Box 209, Folder 2)
  - Slides - BW [sets 1,2,3] + BWMLN (Box 209, Folder 3)
  - Lantern slides; chance fluctuations and other presentations (Card-box 444)
  - Adac-Mairie de Paris, 1996 (Box 350, Folder 1)
  - Fort Lauderdale, Fall 1987; gordon research conference 1985, 1986, 1988, 1990 (Box 350, Folder 2)
  - Science for art prize ceremony, 1994-1995 (Box 350, Folder 3)
  - Photographs and correspondence from Phillippe Lavialle, 1996-1997 (Box 350, Folder 4)
  - Sudbury, 1986 (Box 350, Folder 5)
  - Photographs and correspondence from Alessandro Sderci, 1997. (Box 350, Folder 6)
  - Photographs and correspondence from Kira Od, 1989 (Box 350, Folder 7)
  - Photograph and correspondence from Henri Barbier (Box 350, Folder 13)
  - Photographs: Deutsche Bundesbank, Nov. 2005 (Box 350, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: 11th international conference on fracture. Turin 2005 (Box 350, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Lecture at MIT; MIT 2001; Australia 1990. UC Riverside 2000; K. Brennan School, New Haven, January 1988. (Box 350, Folder 10)
  - Corporate technical recognition event, 1982 (Box 350, Folder 11)
  - Bernard Bolzano portraits (photostats) (Box 350, Folder 12)
  - University of St. Andrews (Box 350, Folder 14)
  - Bremen hon. dr. (Box 350, Folder 15)
  - Photographs and correspondence from Rolf Dobelli, 2004; Photographs and correspondence from Edna Margalit, 2004 (Box 350, Folder 16)
  - Photographs: miscellaneous (Box 350, Folder 17)
  - Richard Voss (Box 351, Folder 1)
  - Oliver, November 24, 1992 (Box 351, Folder 2)
  - Misc. fractal art (Box 351, Folder 3)
  - Early fractal art, prints (visual work) (Box 351, Folder 4)
  - Misc. art and correspondence (Box 351, Folder 5)
  - Computer-generated fractal landscapes, oct 1986 (Box 351, Folder 6)
  - M. Laff, plane crumpling art (Box 351, Folder 7)
  - Augusto Giacometti 1989 (Box 351, Folder 8)
  - Berger's model-photos (Box 351, Folder 9)
  - Fractal images (photographs) removed from plastic photo album (Box 351, Folder 10)
  - Transparencies, fractal landscape images and others (Box 351, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Benoit B. Mandelbrot (Box 352, Folders 1-2)
  - Photographs musgrave (thornwood) (Box 352, Folder 3)
  - Official photographs, all sizes. W. Smith (Box 352, Folder 4)
  - Original cover magazine (Box 352, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Benoit B. Mandelbrot (Box 352, Folders 6-10)
  - Benoit B. Mandelbrot, portraits from envelope "Dentsu incorporated" (Box 352, Folder 11)
  - Photographs: Family and personal (Box 352, Folders 12-13)
  - Photograph: Benoit B. Mandelbrot, 1974 (Box 352, Folder 14)
  - Jeffey Ventrella (Box 351, Folder 11)
  - Tel Aviv University, honorary degree ceremony (photo album) (Flat-box 480, Folder 1)
  - James M. Bearden, fractal landscape (Box 351, Folder 13)
  - Slides, 2-D and 3-D objects (Box 351, Folder 14)
  - Heinz-Otto Petigen, fractal images (negatives) (Box 351, Folder 15)
  - Fractal Planet Rise and other images (negatives) (Box 351, Folder 16)
  - Les Crateres de la Lune (image printed on thermal paper) (Box 351, Folder 17)
  - G. Binning, computer art (Box 351, Folder 18)
  - Alan Norton, fractal art, 1982 (Box 351, Folder 19)
  - Molecular Graphics, computer art (Box 351, Folder 20)
  - DLA (prints and negatives) (Box 351, Folder 21)
  - Fractal landscapes (Box 351, Folder 22)
  - Fractal landscapes, maps (prints and negatives) (Box 351, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous photocopies of images (Box 351, Folder 24)
  - Portrait of BBM, print on paper (visual work) (Box 351, Folder 25)
  - Portrait of BBM, ink drawing on a napkin (Box 351, Folder 26)
  - Slides – Fractal antenna (Box 481, Folder 1)
  - Michael Michelitsch; photographs and prints of fractal art; also notes and postcard, circa 1989 (Box 481, Folder 2)
  - Benoit Mandelbrot as a child and young adult (photographic prints) (Box 481, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Benoit Mandelbrot; also includes correspondence and notes related to photographs, 1980s (Box 481, Folders 4-6)
  - Photographs of Benoit Mandelbrot; also includes correspondence and notes related to photographs, 1990s (Box 481, Folders 7-11)
  - Photographs of Benoit Mandelbrot; also includes correspondence and notes related to photographs, 2000s (Box 481, Folders 12-13)
  - Photographs of Benoit Mandelbrot; also includes correspondence and notes related to photographs (Box 482, Folders 1-7)
  - Official IBM photograph of Benoit Mandelbrot, Paris - 1982 (Box 482, Folder 8)
  - Photograph of Benoit Mandelbrot, Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm – 1984 (Box 482, Folder 9)
  - Fractal landscape, color prints and note (Box 482, Folder 10)
  - Fractal-related art (photographic print and negative); photographed by Robert E. Mates and Paul Katz (Box 482, Folder 11)
  - Fractal train, color prints (visual works) (Box 482, Folder 12)
  - Portraits of BBM (photographic prints) (Flat-box 492, Folder 1)
  - Penn State conference/talk, photograph, 1994 (Flat-box 492, Folder 2)
  - A.T Fomenko, photographs (Flat-box 348, Folder 8)
  - Gordon Conference, photograph (Flat-box 491, Folders 11)
- Series 25. Music
  This small series contains music scores and album covers for computer music and music inspired by fractal geometry.
  - Larry Austin et al., Computer Music (record cover and LP record), 1983 (Flat-box 471, Folder 2)
  - Charles Wuorinen, conductor (stage bill) (Box 503, Folders 11)
  - Software, Syn-Code (record cover and booklet) (Flat-box 471, Folder 1)
  - Harri Vuori, Mandelbrot Echoes (music score), 1995 (Flat-box 471, Folder 3)
  - Claude A. Coppens, Mandelbrot Set (music score), 1999-2000 (Flat-box 471, Folder 4)
  - Trevor Bacca, Poeme Recusrsif (music score), 2003 (Flat-box 471, Folder 5)
  - Gyorgi Ligeti, Artikulation; Electronic Music (poster) (Map-folder 526)
  - "Fractal Music" notes, Harlan Brothers (Half-box 533, Folder 11)
- Series 26. Audiovisual Material
  This series contains audio and video material in a range formats, including film reels, data tapes, Betacam, U-matic, VHS, audiocassetes, and DVDs. Audio and video material consists of recorded lectures, television and radio interviews, animation, fractal-related music compositions, and documentaries.
  Access to Collection
  The majority of audiovisual material in the collection has been digitally reformatted and is available to view in the Special Collections Reading Room.
  Film reels and 8mm data tapes have not been digitized. Researchers wishing to view an item in one of these formats must request that the item be reformatted to a digital use copy.
  - Fractals: An Animated Discussion. With Edward Lorenz and Benoit B. Mandelbrot. Animations--Experiements. A Film by H.-O. Peitgen, H. Jurgens, D. Saupe, C. Zahlten (VHS), 1990 (Box AV-01, Item 1)
    63 min
  - NY Notes (VHS) (Box AV-01, Item 2)
  - SIGGRAPH Video Review. An optional supplement to the ACM SIGGRAPH publication Compuer Graphics. Issues 81 & 82: SIGGRAPH '92 Electronic Theater (VHS), 1992 (Box AV-01, Item 3)
  - Works and Process produced by Mary Sharp Cronson. New York Notes. (VHS), 1990 Apr 19-20 (Box AV-01, Item 4)
    Case title is "Music and Fractals Guggenheim NY Notes"
  - Fractals 1992, 3D DL [Harting] a few minutes. SIGGRAPH 1992. Started 25 Jul 1992 (VHS) (Box AV-01, Item 5)
  - Clouds Are Not Spheres: The Fractal Theory of Benoit Mandelbrot. Films for the Humanities & Sciences 19015 (VHS), 2004-01-12 (Box AV-01, Item 6)
  - The Beauty and Use of Fractals, Benoit Mandelbrot, Abraham Robinson Adjunct Professor of Mathematical Sciences at the University of Yale and IBM Fellow Emeritus at IBM T J Watson Research Centre (VHS), 1999 (Box AV-01, Item 7)
  - Zdenka Cechova: 1/ Cosmos 16', 2/ Contrasts of the Life 6', 3/ Beautiful City Kyoto 10' (VHS) (Box AV-01, Item 8)
  - Gala des Technologies de la Creation, Paris Cite 1990. Paris Cite, Concours International des Technologies de la Creation (VHS) (Box AV-01, Item 9)
    "1 segment on fractal geometry in French. Not great not [?] format"
  - Science and the Written Word, Guest: Dr. Benoit Mandelbrot, IBM Fellow, Sterling Professor, Yale (VHS), 2004-01-14 (Box AV-01, Item 10)
    CUNY TV
  - Clouds Are Not Spheres, Gordon Films UK (VHS) (Box AV-01, Item 11)
    52 min.
  - Benoit Mandelbrot Creativity 2000 (VHS), 2000-06-21 (Box AV-02, Item 1)
  - Fractales FR3 NTSC Radio? + Interview in French, very good (VHS) (Box AV-02, Item 2)
  - Arthur C. Clarke Presents: The Colours of Infinity. Gordon Films UK (VHS) (Box AV-02, Item 3)
    "Tom, Benoit would like to have these back when you are finished. Chris"
  - LVMH Science Pour L'Art Ceremonie-Linda Buck. TRT: 15:10 (VHS), 1992-11-19 (Box AV-02, Item 4)
    12:15:10 AM
  - Executive Council Videos 2 pieces, B B Mandelbrot Fractal Group (VHS) (Box AV-02, Item 5)
    "from Benoit-- You'll need the glasses for the second half."
  - [no title] (VHS) (Box AV-02, Item 6)
  - Truncated Fractals in Forced Oscillators, Matthew Varghese, Cornell University, 1988 (VHS) (Box AV-02, Item 7)
    "Demo--no voice". "Matthew Varghese (1988), Electrical Engineering, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 14853"
  - [no title] (VHS) (Box AV-02, Item 8)
  - Fractal (degital) © 1991, 92; Chaos (degital) © 1984; Optical howling (analog) © 1972, 74, 75, 78. Kiyoshi IWATA (VHS) (Box AV-02, Item 9)
    [additional text in Japanese]
  - "The Originals" Gore Vidal, John Polanyi (VHS) (Box AV-02, Item 10)
  - Professor Devaney Explains The Fractal Geometry of the Mandelbrot Set (VHS), 1996 (Box AV-02, Item 11)
  - A Science Television Production. Chaos, Fractals and Dynamics: Computer Experiments in Mathematics with Robert Devaney (VHS), 1989 (Box AV-02, Item 12)
    "8/30/97 Teaching fractals. Nothing on Mandelbrot set. Boring lecture. J. J. Wynne"
  - Third NTT Science Forum. Fractals: The Beauty and their Applications, 1992, April 17, Tosho Hall. Panel Discussion: Part 1 (VHS), 1992-04-17 (Box AV-03, Item 1)
  - A Science Television Production. Chaos, Fractals and Dynamics: Computer Experiments in Mathematics with Robert Devaney (VHS), 1989 (Box AV-03, Item 2)
  - Third NTT Science Forum. Fractals: The Beauty and their Applications, 1992, April 17, Tosho Hall. Dr. B. B. Mandelbrot (VHS), 1992-04-17 (Box AV-03, Item 3)
  - The Fractal World, Shigehiro Ushiki, NTT R&D Information and Patent Center, Dai-Ichi Nikken Corporation (VHS) (Box AV-03, Item 4)
  - "Fractal Fest" - Dr. Benoit Mandelbrot, Channel 8 WFAA-TV (ABC) 05/16/92 10:00 PM (VHS), 1992-05-16 (Box AV-03, Item 5)
    3:00:00 AM
  - Fractal Fantasy, Duncan Brinsmead (VHS), 1987 (Box AV-03, Item 6)
    "8/30/97 So-so animation through serpienski cube and over landscape. J J Wynne"
  - Clouds Are Not Spheres, SCETV version, Gordon Films (VHS), 2000-12-18 (Box AV-03, Item 7)
  - Benoit Mandelbrot: Famous Modern Day Mathemetician (VHS) (Box AV-03, Item 8)
  - The Mathematical Sciences Research Institute presents Mathematics in Arcadia, Tom Stoppard in Conversation with Robert Osserman (VHS), 1999-02-19 (Box AV-03, Item 9)
  - SIGGRAPH, Alan Norton, IBM 1986 (Box AV-03, Item 10)
    "Alan Norton, Ithaca NY 14853. Please return: Judy Warren B49 Caldwell Hall
  - CBS Six O'clock News with Jim Jensen. Health and Science Watch 1987 (VHS) (Box AV-03, Item 11)
  - Ceremonie de remise des diplomes aux X 94 (VHS), 1997-07-12 (Box AV-03, Item 12)
    1 hr 40 min
  - Fractals: the Colors of Infinity. Films for the Humanities and Sciences (VHS) (Box AV-03, Item 13)
  - Gaea Zoom (VHS), 1994-09 (Box AV-04, Item 1)
  - V 2598 Mandelbrot. Institut fur den Wissenschaftlichen Film (VHS) (Box AV-04, Item 2)
    "Rough cut. NOT to be reproduced, ONLY to show privately how the tape will be"
  - ? (VHS) (Box AV-04, Item 3)
  - Laplacian Fracal Growth. Carl Evertsz, Pier Siebesma & Ferdinand Oeinck (VHS), 1988 (Box AV-04, Item 4)
  - [no title] (VHS) (Box AV-04, Item 5)
  - [Carl Evertsz] PAL version (VHS) (Box AV-04, Item 6)
  - Ma+h…who needs it?! With Jaime Escalante (VHS), 1991 (Box AV-04, Item 7)
    58 min
  - ACM SIGGRAPH '88 Exhibition of Computer Art. Catalog of Interactivfe Installations and Video (VHS), 1988 (Box AV-04, Item 8)
    "(Fractal Fantasy, Brinsmead)" [highlighted on case]
  - Spektrum. May we introduce ourselves? (VHS) (Box AV-04, Item 9)
  - Eyescape: an excursion in ambient video (VHS), 1994 (Box AV-04, Item 10)
    "8/30/97 Interesting music, Stills with color cycling. Meant to relax, not excite. J J Wynne"
  - Professor Cornelius Lanczos (VHS) (Box AV-04, Item 11)
    "Professor Lanczos Part 2"
    56 min
  - Machine Dreams / Maschinentraume (VHS) (Box AV-05, Item 1)
    Barfuss Film, Sulzburgstr. 113, 5000 Koln 41
  - Gaea Zoom, Ken Musgrave (VHS), 1995-03-16 (Box AV-05, Item 2)
  - Bubbles & Soap Films (VHS) (Box AV-05, Item 3)
  - Bubbles and Soap Films, Geometry Supercomputer Project (VHS) (Box AV-05, Item 4)